Kshitij Mamgain

LinkedIn: http://linkedin.com/in/kshitij-mamgain

Email: <u>kshitij.mamgain@gmail.com</u> Portfolio: <u>https://kshitijmamgain.github.io/</u>

Mobile: 437-216-1818; Toronto ON

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with more than 4+ years of experience in analytics and statistical modeling to solve complex business problems with strong knowledge of SQL and solid skills in <u>data munging & visualization</u>, <u>machine</u> learning and statistical modules in Python and R.

SKILLS

Expert: Machine Learning, ETL, Data Analytics, Modular Coding, Testing

Technical: Python, SQL, R, Cloud Computing, Shell Scripting, Scikit Learn, Keras, Tensorflow

Business: Agile Project Management, Active learner, Interpersonal skills, Team-player

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Research Assistant, Lantern Institute, ON

2020 - Present

- Draft white paper to compare ML algorithms using Bayesian optimization for parameter tuning.
- Develop Python packages for preprocessing, feature engineering and prepare bash script to run on GCP.
- Manage the project as a scrum master in an agile environment as a Google Cloud project.

XGBoost, Catboost, Statistical Analysis, Hyperopt, Shell Scripting (<u>link</u>)

Data Science Fellow, Lantern Institute, ON

2019 - 2020

Samsung Health Data Analysis

- Designed dashboard to analyse behavior pattern on real world data and deployed as a web app
- Performed data cleaning, transformation to extract user information using sqlite and pandas

Plotly, Dash, SQL, Heroku, Time Series Analysis

Credit Card Fraud

• Designed a unique framework using boosted trees algorithm to get state of art performance results.

Auto Encoder, XGBoost, Catboost, Keras, Sklearn, Modeling

Program Data Analyst, Tata Trusts, Delhi, India

2017 - 2019

- Presented analysis and resulting recommendations dashboards in Tableau for effective communication.
- Automated dashboards on social impacts through data processing from multiple sources using SQL.
- Utilized analytical and statistical rigor to drive business decisions on program outreach and impact.

Tableau, Data Analytics, Statistical Modeling, ETL Processes

Program Associate, Tata Trusts, India

2014 - 2016

• Analyzed program related data on Management Information System and budget by running queries.

**Agile Business Development , Data Collection and Modeling, Time Management*

Solution Engineer, Nokia Solutions Network, India

2010 - 2012

• Provided technical solutions to the global customer teams on packet networks and data networking.

Technical Solutions, Stakeholder Collaboration, Communication

EDUCATION

•	Advanced Diploma in Data Science and Application, Metro College, Toronto	2019 - 2020
•	MPhil in Development Studies, Ambedkar University Delhi, India	2012 - 2014
•	BEng in Electronics and Communication, Maharshi Dayanand Univ., India	2006 - 2010